Jordan O'Hara

41A Ditchling Rd, BN1 4SB Tel: 07542 874932 Email: J.O'Hara2@uni.brighton.ac.uk

Profile

I am second-year BSc (Hons) Software Engineering student at the University of Brighton with a background in Web Software Development and on track to achieve a First. I am highly motivated and believe communication is crucial to a great team; I enjoy interacting with customers and staff to offer quality service. I can pick up skills quickly and am highly adaptable. Through my studies and varied work experience I have developed a broad skillset and I am eager to learn and progress. I am very keen to secure a sandwich year in industry to further apply and develop my software skills and gain valuable professional experience.

<u>Skills</u>

- Java programming skills (1-2 Years)
- HTML and CSS (5 Years)
- JavaScript (5 Years)
- CSS (5 Years)
- TypeScript (2 Year)
- Quick learner with a positive and professional attitude
- Strong teamworking skills
- Excellent communication and organisational skills

If you like to preview some of my work, it can be found here: https://github.com/jo372

Achievements and Interests

I enjoy spending my free time volunteering my IT skills to a charity called Seeds of Growth to contribute to a worthy cause. I am proud that I was Course Rep for Software Engineering in Year 1 where I was able to take, communicate and act on my fellow students' ideas and suggestions about the course in hopes to improve it for the newcomers.

Education

University of Brighton BSc (Hons) Software Engineering Sept 2019 – Present Predicted grade 1:1

Modules Include:

- Introduction to Programming (82%): allowed me to develop upon my programming experience. While this was only an introduction, I spent most of my time learning about the Software development life cycle and how to make my code more readable and usable for other developers.
- Introduction to Web Development (85%): While it only covered the basic, it allowed me to build upon my previous experiences as a Web Software Developer. I was able to use my previous knowledge to help teach my classmates when they were struggling.
- Working in the Computing Industry (72%): This module allowed me to work alongside some of
 my classmates and gave me some insight into what it is like to work with others. There were times
 where we struggled but we'd meet up at least once a week to make sure the project was on task
 and finished by the deadline.

Bexhill 6th Form College, Bexhill

2013 - 2015

BTEC Level 3 National Extended Diploma: IT - DDM

GCSE: English: C;

Robertsbridge Community College, Robertsbridge

2008 - 2013

GCSE: English: D; Maths: B; Science: C; Science Additional: D; R.E: C; I.C.T FS: Pass; Art:

E; Music: D; Drama: C

Employment

Seeds of Growth (Charity), Hastings Office Administrator

Oct 2018 - Present

Working as a volunteer in the busy office my role includes maintaining office records, filing and document management, contacting clients via email, creating advertisement posters, leaflets, brochures etc. and managing the charity's GoFundMe and Social Media Pages and the website. I enjoy offering a quality customer service and fit in well to the team.

Adecco, Hastings Retail Assistant, Sainsbury's **Christmas 2018**

Working through the Agency over Christmas I work in a busy Sainsbury's store. My role was to put new stock out on display, clean and tidy the shelves, help customers with enquiries and keep the floors clear. I enjoyed offering good customer service and was able to work varied shifts.

Oxfam, Hastings Retail Assistant Mar 2018 - May 2018

Providing customer service including greeting customers and helping them to find various products and answering customer enquiries, sorting and pricing the inventory, putting stock out on the shop floor, removing old items and moving them to other Oxfam locations.

Koneqt, Hastings Software Developer 2016 - 2017

Having gained an Apprenticeship, my job was to create UI Designs using HTML, CSS & Javascript, create dynamic pages using an Ajax feed and optimised ajax feeds, create PHP scripts which would return a JSON feed, dependent on parameters passed. (PostgreSQL) and developed POS Systems, CRMs, job boards and web-based applications.

References available upon Request